# Kishan Rasikbhai Akbari

709-202-9994

kishanakbari@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/kishan-rasikbhai-akbari/

#### **OBJECTIVE**

An engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the mechanical/aerospace industry. In my professional career I have worked with some of the top core engineering firms. While working on some of the industry problems, I realised about my interest towards statistics and data science.

Currently, I am exploring the field of Artificial Intelligent (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) and looking forward to implement it into engineering.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Master's Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

Indian Institute of Technology Madras, Chennai

## Bachelor's Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Jun 2011 - Jul 2015

Faculty of Technology and Engineering, Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara

#### **SKILLS**

Programming: Python, SQL, MATLAB

Data Tools: MS Excel, Tableau, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Machine Learning

CAD packages: Solidworks, Auto CAD, Creo Parametric, CADfix

Simulation/Tools: COMSOL Multiphysics, ANSYS, SC03, Siemens NX, Abaqus

Documentation: MS Office, LATEX

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Engineering Lead**

Jan 2021 - Present

Infosys Ltd

FE modeling and analysis of Gas Turbine Engine externals components.

## **Advanced Stress Engineer**

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd

Worked on FEA modelling and Stress analysis of Gas turbine Engine combustor components.

#### Component Engineer Mechanical Analyst

Feb 2019 - Sep 2019

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd • Bangalore

Contributed to the development of on-fleet repair documents for mechanical components of Gas Turbine Engine.

Supported design and optimisation of mechanical components for Gas Turbine Engine.

Contributed to the continuous improvement projects for cost and time saving in engineering workflow.

# **Engineering Graduate**

Jul 2017 - Jan 2019

Rolls-Royce India Pvt Ltd • Bangalore

Investigated the testing failure of gas turbine engine and proved the hypothesis behind the problem.

Contributed to the development of automatic calculation tool as a part of process improvement initiative.

# **AWARDS AND HONOURS**

# **ABB JDF Scholarship**

2012

Awarded ABB JDF scholarship for exceptional academic as well as extra-curricular record.

# **University Gold Medal**

2015

Awarded Gold Medal for excellent achievement in the Design of Machine Element course from M.S. University.